<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on JG</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on JG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.129.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Medical images registration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/projects/medical-images-registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/projects/medical-images-registration/</guid>
      <description>A key challenge in biomedical image analysis and particularly in brain image analysis is registration; human anatomical variability is the norm, necessitating the transformation of image data into standard coordinates. This standardization facilitates analysis and allows results to be generalized to a larger population.
Affine registration, which uses linear transformations, provides a robust initial alignment of overall brain structures. This is followed by diffeomorphic registration, which models smooth, non-linear deformations to capture intricate anatomical details.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion-weighted imaging theory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/projects/dwi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/projects/dwi/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s an overview of how MRI works:
Magnetic Alignment: The MRI scanner generates a strong magnetic field that aligns the protons in the body&amp;rsquo;s hydrogen atoms, which are abundant in water and fat.
Radiofrequency Pulses: The scanner then emits RF pulses at a specific frequency that matches the resonance frequency of the aligned protons. These pulses provide energy, causing the protons to tip out of their alignment with the magnetic field (for example, a 90° RF pulse tips the aligned protons by 90 degrees from their inital alignment with the main magnetic field (B0), from $ z $-axis to transverse plane ($x-y$ plane), this tipping creates a detectable signal in the MRI receiver coil).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
