<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>JG</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on JG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.129.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion-weighted imaging theory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/projects/dwi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/projects/dwi/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s an overview of how MRI works:
Magnetic Alignment: The MRI scanner generates a strong magnetic field that aligns the protons in the body&amp;rsquo;s hydrogen atoms, which are abundant in water and fat.
Radiofrequency Pulses: The scanner then emits RF pulses at a specific frequency that matches the resonance frequency of the aligned protons. These pulses provide energy, causing the protons to tip out of their alignment with the magnetic field (for example, a 90° RF pulse tips the aligned protons by 90 degrees from their inital alignment with the main magnetic field (B0), from $ z $-axis to transverse plane ($x-y$ plane), this tipping creates a detectable signal in the MRI receiver coil).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fireworks in Venice , the Feast of the Redeemer, By Vincenzo Abbati (Italian,1803 – 1866)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/gallery/p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/JulienGenzling.github.io/gallery/p1/</guid>
      <description>Fireworks in Venice, the Feast of the Redeemer By Vincenzo Abbati (Italian, 1803 – 1866)
Overview: &amp;ldquo;Fireworks in Venice, the Feast of the Redeemer&amp;rdquo; is a painting by the Italian artist Vincenzo Abbati. The painting captures the vibrant and festive atmosphere of one of Venice&amp;rsquo;s most significant annual events, the Festa del Redentore (Feast of the Redeemer).
About the Artist: Name: Vincenzo Abbati Born: 1803 Died: 1866 Nationality: Italian Known For: Abbati was renowned for his skill in depicting architectural interiors and cityscapes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
